# **Michael Nugent**

# Software Engineer

## **Summary**

Recent BS Computer Science graduate with strengths in object oriented programming, full stack web development, software engineering concepts, and soft skills. Demonstrated work ethic through a decade of non-tech-industry work experience. Possesses portfolio of high-quality academic projects at personal website.

#### Contact

NugentMichael@live.com

NugentMichael.com

(949) 293-5705

Irvine, CA

#### **Education**

**BS** Computer Science

California State University,

Fresno

August 2022

magna cum laude

#### Skills

**Object Oriented Programming** 

- C / C++
- JavaScript

Web Development

- React
- Node / Express
- MySQL / NoSQL
- Full Stack
- REST

Software Engineering

- Cohesion / Coupling
- SOLID Principles
- Testing
- UML Diagrams
- Architectures

#### Soft Skills

- Teamwork
- Problem Solving
- Communication
- Critical Thinking

## **Work Experience**

02/2017 to 08/2018 **OTR Driver**, Prime Inc. – Springfield, MO

Transported refrigerated products through all 48 contiguous states. Met appointments, efficiently managed fuel expenditure, and successfully complied with government time regulations through rigorous logistics.

10/2014 to 01/2016 **Background Actor**, Central Casting – Burbank, CA

Worked with 2<sup>nd</sup> Assistant Directors to implement choreography, select wardrobe, and authentically portray atmosphere characters for television and movie scenes.

03/2013 to 09/2014 **Cashier**, Starplex Cinemas – Irvine, CA

Took concession orders, sold tickets, restocked supplies, cleaned theaters, ensured movie quality, and fielded guest complaints.

03/2011 to 05/2012 **Student Technician**, California State University, Fresno – Fresno, CA

Assisted faculty, staff, and students in computer related tasks through product research, skills development, and feature testing.

### **Academic Project Samples**

Web Development – "Gomoku"

LAMP stack web development foundations project. Used HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, and MySQL to implement a local frontend client and backend server to achieve database CRUD operations: user registration and login, game victory record updates and fetches; and OOP logic to enable complex game-play. Later, updated project to a single-page application with a Model-View-Controller architecture that uses the React framework, and Google Firebase's NoSQL Firestore database.

Software Engineering – "RoadMap"

Worked as part of an agile team to design and build an academic guidance web application for students through the MERN (MongoDB, Express, React, and Node) stack. Established system requirements, and implemented unit and integration tests through the Jest framework. Created UML class, sequence, and use-case diagrams. Practiced SOLID principles to achieve code readability and maintainability.